Farming Life in Another World
When you open your eyes and see
that pure white light, the story begins
Stepping forth into a new world,
what kind of flowers will we make bloom?
Even if it's cloudy,
even if we get dirty from a puddle
We continue on
There's a future we can't imagine
waiting for us, I'm sure of it
Meeting, meeting, and connecting
If you smile,
everyone around you will smile too
Let's plant a small seed and nurture it
One day it'll become a large flower
Turn regrets and failures into fuel
So that you're overflowing with colorful happiness
We'll join hands and share
Spread across the world, Flower Ring
Today we're all enjoying
another peaceful morning.
The Great Tree Village
has become quite lively lately.
One, two...
My day starts once the sun has
completely risen each morning.
That's when I wake up.
Good morning.
Hey, good morning.
Are you feeling alright?
Jeez, you ask me that
every time you see me.
Oh, do I?
But I'm sure things are tough for you.
Once we found out that
Lu was pregnant,
the entire village went into a joyous uproar.
So that's why I haven't been
able to transform.
I-is that how it works?
She was the calmest out of everyone.
You don't need to worry so much.
I'm sure everything will be fine.
Is that right?
It is.
I'm going to go check on
the medicinal herb garden.
Okay. Are you alright going by yourself?
You're doing it again.
Ah, sorry.
Now back to my morning schedule.
According to Anne and the maids,
it's my job to keep an eye
on things around the house.
Good morning.
Hey. Morning.
By the way, there's a reason I don't
wake up too early in the morning.
Anne and the other maids all insist on
waking up earlier than I do.
I sleep later for their sakes.
I'm definitely not being lazy.
When I see her in the morning,
she lets me know if she has
anything to report.
Last night the wine slime
snuck into the food storage area
and drank and entire barrel of wine.
Was that the barrel that we left out
to keep the wine slime away from the rest?
Yes. I'm not sure if we should
celebrate our plan working,
or if we should be lamenting the fact
that we let it sneak in at all.
Let's just say it went according to plan.
Once I've made my rounds around the house,
it's time for breakfast.
We can't fit everyone into
the dining hall at once,
so we split breakfast up
into three groups.
For today's main breakfast menu,
we have a soup of daikon radish,
spinach, and cabbage.
We also have smoked killer rabbit
that we've seared to finish.
Thank you.
It looks great.
One microorganism, two microorganisms...
Flora?
Have you not been sleeping?
One microorganism, two microorganisms...
I haven't been making any progress
on the miso production.
Taste-testing miso
I guess this is about 20% of the way there...
It's because you say stuff like that.
I'm sure I just need more of this stuff.
I apologize, and I implore you
to get some sleep.
The second breakfast group is the maids.
Finally, the third group
is whoever didn't make it in time
for the first or second groups.
Sometimes Hakuren doesn't even
make it in time for the third group.
Mayor, I'm here to make a report.
Did something happen?
Yesterday, a group of three killer rabbits
attempted to infiltrate the village.
However, Kuro and the dogs
were able to eliminate them.
I see.
Those rabbits never learn their lesson.
Well, we are able to use them as food,
so we should be thankful that
they act the way they do.
Good point.
You know, even though
Granmaria and the other angels
always seem so composed and proper,
they all enter lazy mode when they're
off duty and on their own time.
They can't really do any chores.
Anne and the maids prepare their food,
while they rely on Daga
and the other lizardmen
to do their laundry and other cleaning.
Well, they do make up for it with how hard
they work to keep the village safe.
I'm glad we have them here.
Hey. Good morning.
Once I've eaten, it's time to
move onto working the fields.
These things again?
None of the normal garden pests
I'm familiar with exist in this world,
Garden Pest (probably)
but instead we have these
weird little black things
that live on the plants and eat their leaves.
Fortunately, Zabuton's kids or Kuro and
the other dogs can spot them for us,
so as of now, they've yet to cause
any real damage.
And the way I deal with them is...
using the almighty farming tool
as a watering can.
Apparently, it has the power to
eliminate garden pests.
The fields that we've been slowly expanding
have become quite large in size.
Checking on all of them is pretty tough now.
But seeing all the matured crops
fills me with joy,
and with a sense of satisfaction
for all the work we've done.
While I'm working on my chores,
lunch time comes around.
I eat the lunch that Anne and the maids
prepared in between my work.
Apparently, having lunch in this world
is very out of the ordinary.
A meal in the afternoon?
But we just ate this morning.
I felt the same way when I first came here.
Lunch aside, Lea and the high elves
were nervous about even eating breakfast.
Is it okay if we eat today, too?
Will our food reserves hold out at this rate?
According to them, they weren't always
able to eat even a single meal each day.
You mean we get to eat food every day?
We're definitely going to get kicked out
of this village, aren't we?!
How did she reach that conclusion?
I want to make sure that none of them
have to worry about food
as long as they're living here.
Mayor.
The cows gave birth to calves.
I'd like to increase their allotted feed.
Yeah, take care of that.
Mayor, our crop storage room
is going to be completely full soon.
Shall we talk to Michael about
selling more of what we produce?
Yeah, let's talk to Flow
and then decide on how much.
After lunch time ends, it's back to work.
Having more people around
has helped with the farmwork a lot.
But tilling new fields or planting new crops
is something I handle myself
with the almighty farming tool.
Up until now, I've only been
growing stuff we could eat,
but I think adding a little color
to our village
is good for making things
feel more civilized.
Outside of the farmwork I do,
the villagers ask me to build
all sorts of little things for them.
Thanks to the almighty farming tool,
I can manage to make things
for them even though I have
no experience in construction.
Once again, I thank God for these blessings.
I also...
like to occasionally join everyone
for their battle training.
I'd like to think we'll never need
this training living here,
but Anne and the maids strongly advised
we hold regular training
just in case anything should happen.
Oh well, getting some more exercise
is good for everyone's health.
Okay, let's keep going!
If we keep eating the way
we do in this village,
one day we'll no longer be able to fit
into our sacred maid uniforms!
I think mine's already starting to
become a tighter fit!
Let's go!
Maybe I need some more exercise...
I'm already at my limit.
I bet I'd be better with that one!
Can I try it out?
Sure, I don't mind.
This is harder than I thought.
I guess I'm really not suited
to use normal weapons.
But I still have this spear!
That was amazing! How did you do that?
I'm not exactly sure when I can use this...
Once the sun starts to set,
I wrap up the work I was doing
and head home.
Oh, I've never seen this dish before.
This is the new menu item
we're trying out today.
It's simmered killer rabbit
served with a sweet honey sauce.
How confident are you?
About 20%.
That's pretty low...
It's sweet!
If possible, I'd like you to only present dishes
that you have at least 50% confidence in...
I cannot do that.
We cannot afford to waste food.
Good point.
I did my best to enjoy the meal.
At dinner time, a lot more people
gather around the table.
We take the chance to report anything
that we want everyone to hear.
Mayor.
Princess Yuri has sent a letter.
Wonder what it is.
Let's see... "I'd like to eat the apples
from your village again.
Also, I'd like a dress."
What is this?
She really liked the clothes
that Zabuton made
and was wondering if she
could have more made for her.
I see.
I apologize. I'll tell her to stop
making so many requests.
Well, I'm sure Zabuton will be
happy to make something for her.
Once I've rested a bit after dinner,
it's bath time.
I pretty much have the men's
bathhouse all to myself.
I couldn't really relax when
we only had one bathhouse.
I'm really glad I forced them
to build a men's bathhouse.
This is paradise.
After I get out of the bath,
it's time to relax...
or at least I wish it was.
This is usually where
I start to feel uneasy.
He's about to enter his house.
I've got eyes on him here.
He's headed straight for his bedroom.
Understood.
Why is it that I can still feel their eyes
on me even though I'm inside my room?
Ah! Someone help me!
Our cover is blown!
Everyone, retreat!
I'm sure they're just keeping watch
because they want to keep me safe.
That's what I tell myself.
Oh well.
Even with stuff like that happening,
I couldn't be happier with
my everyday life here.
God, thank you once again for giving me
a second chance at life here.
I'll do my best again tomorrow.
I need to have those hidden doors
sealed up tomorrow.
Farming Life...
in Another...
World.
Whether it's day or night here in the village,
Donovan and the dwarves are always
hard at work making alcohol.
When it comes to dwarves,
Dwarves
Donovan
Cross
Wilcox
I used to imagine them being merry
and getting drunk all the time.
There's no way we could possibly produce
good alcohol if we were drunk while working!
Indeed, you're right.
Even the man in charge of
watching the fire would...
The man in charge of the fire
drinking on the job?
Out of the question!
That could cause a fire!
Indeed, you're right.
As you can see,
they take their job very seriously.
I think this one came out pretty good.
Nope. This one's no good.
It's lost its flavor and aroma.
This is bad booze that does nothing
but burn your throat.
So, are you going to throw it away?
Nope.
We've still got uses for this.
We'll distill it some more
and then cut it with fruit juice.
Alright, back to the drawing board.
Let's rethink how we're distilling it.
I have nothing but respect for
the passion with which they make alcohol.
Hey, mayor.
Could you increase the amount
of grapes we're harvesting?
I need three times
what we're harvesting now.
Okay... I'll see what I can do.
Increase the harvest. Three times.
Three times, huh?
Well, everyone here really loves their wine.
Mayor!
What is it?
There's this... strange man...
A strange man?
It's a strange man!
How did he even make it this far
in the first place?
He made it by Granmaria
and Zabuton without them noticing?
Oh? Is that the Progenitor?
Lulucy!
Um... the Progenitor?
It's been a long time, Progenitor.
You look like you're doing well, Flora.
I am.
When I first heard that Lulucy was with child,
Progenitor of the Vampires
Vargryfe
I was sure there must have been
some sort of mistake.
It looks like I was wrong.
Yes. I'm quite surprised myself.
That's right.
We vampires usually continue our bloodline
by forming new bloodpacts.
This rarely happens.
But children are a treasure,
and you must take care of yours.
I will. Thank you.
What do you mean he's the Progenitor?
To put it simply, I guess you could say
he's like our grandfather.
Grandfather?
That's right.
I'm about 4,000 years old now.
4,000?
I forget the exact number.
I can't see him as anything other than
a regular young guy.
The trick to leading such a long life
is to occasionally erase your memories.
Your memories?
I make sure to keep the important stuff
like my name and the clan I belong to,
and then I make everything else
go poof and forget about it.
It goes poof? Isn't that kind of scary?
It was scary the first time,
but I got used to it after that.
It's only been about 200 years since
the last time I erased my memories,
so I still feel pretty young now.
I didn't know vampires had that ability.
We don't. I use magic for that.
Magic sounds really useful.
By the way, I'm really sorry that I
entered the village without saying hello.
I'd originally planned to just have
a look around and then quietly leave,
but I was drawn in by a certain presence.
A presence?
That statue below the big tree!
It's wonderful!
It's a splendid likeness of
the great creator!
Before I knew it, I was bowing.
Ah, that's what you meant.
Does that mean you've met God before?
Yes. Just once, when I was born.
He told me to do my best
even though I would be born with
a slightly abnormal body.
And by abnormal body he meant vampire?
I believe so.
Thanks to that, I feel like
I've faced a lot of hardships
and been saved a number of times...
But I can't be sure since
I've erased my memories!
Oh well, I get the feeling
that I've done my best!
Okay.
However, I do remember the creator.
It's just that for some reason,
I can't remember his exact appearance.
Was he an old man?
Or maybe a young man?
What color were his eyes?
What color was his hair?
I've tried numerous times
to create a likeness of him,
but I've never created anything
as accurate as that.
I'm sure living nearby
a masterpiece like that...
means that every single day
of your life is amazing!
It must be so nice!
I'm so jealous!
He wants it, right?
Um, about that statue...
It belongs to the village,
so I don't think I can offer it to you.
I knew it. I get it. But it's too bad...
But it's too bad...
It's too bad, huh?
Too bad...
If you'd like,
I could make you a new one.
I'm not a sculptor, so I'm not sure
if you'll like what I make or not.
Really?
I'd love that!
I'm so happy. Thank you!
How do you like it?
I think he likes it.
I think you're right.
Sorry for the sudden request.
How much should I pay you for it?
Nothing. I can't take money for this.
God isn't something
that you're supposed to sell.
I see.
Then I'll have to think about
something else I can do as thanks.
Lu.
Make sure you give birth to a healthy baby.
I will.
Good health to you too, Flora.
And you as well, Progenitor.
Thank you for everything, mayor.
I'm grateful for this statue,
and for what you've done for Lu.
Keep taking care of her, okay?
I will.
I was a little surprised at first,
but he seems like an easygoing guy.
He sure is.
And to think, he's such an incredibly
important and high-ranking person.
Is he really that important?
My lord!
Welcome back.
It's been a while.
How many years does this make?
I believe it's been 50 years now.
As you can see, I've become an old man.
So you're in charge of the temple now?
Yes, for about 30 years now.
Well you've always been a devout believer.
You're the man for the job.
Thank you very much.
Has anything changed?
Not a thing. Everything is as it always was.
I see.
I'm glad to hear that,
but there's going to be
a big change starting today.
What might you mean by that?
I want to enshrine this statue
here in this temple.
You do? What kind of statue is that?
You'll just have to wait and see.
I want you to put it in the best spot here.
Well, that would mean...
We'd have to move
the statue of the creator
that was crafted by the
master sculptor, Toorook.
I don't know if we can simply move
the most beloved statue in this temple
from its resting place...
Yeah. Sure we can.
Yes, sir.
This is such... a majestic work of art.
It must have been made by
quite a famous sculptor.
We must be sure that everyone
properly honors their name.
I think it would be better if we didn't.
He doesn't seem like the type
to appreciate stuff like that.
Besides, I don't want to do anything
to disturb his peaceful life.
That is most unfortunate.
But I don't think it would be a problem
if we were to quietly support him.
Indeed.
Let all the other temples know immediately.
Tell them to be respectful of him,
as well as respectful of
The Great Tree Village.
Right away.
Are you okay?
Y-yeah.
That caught me off guard.
It's been a long time since I've sneezed.
The Progenitor sent us a magnificent piano.
I refused to take payment for the statue,
so he said this was a gift
to celebrate Lu's pregnancy.
He's really considerate
for someone so important.
We talked for a while
about where we would put it.
There we go.
We decided to place it
in the village's dining hall.
Thanks guys. Good work.
Good work, everyone.
That piano...
Is it the kind that you would
only find in a large temple?
Yeah. That's the kind of piano
that only gets used for big ceremonies.
Hey, hey.
Do you think it's okay if we play it?
Yeah, this is a once in a lifetime-
No... it's more like a
never in a lifetime chance.
That means if we can play this piano now,
we'll be able to brag about this
for the rest of our lives!
You can go first.
I'm fine with playing later, too.
This thing is way too scary
for us to even try playing!
My hands are sweating so much!
If we break it,
that'll be the end of our lives!
You want another piano?
F-for us to practice on.
Please. We don't mind
if it's old and beat up.
Actually, an old piano would be best.
Can't you play the one we already have?
No, we can't!
Huh? You're crying?
We talked to Michael and had him
procure a practice piano for us.
I don't really know anything about these,
but the one we got from
the Progenitor seems a lot fancier.
Now I feel bad that he sent us
something so nice.
The pianos were hit.
Everyone wanted to play.
The only ones who could already play well
were Flowrem and the girls from
the Demonic Kingdom,
but everyone else seems to enjoy
practicing to get better.
I just wish they'd stop playing at night...
I can feel the soft seasonal winds,
gently on my fingertips
Let's search for what we love
in the clouds floating in the sky
Forget about the hands of the clock for now
Try taking one deep breath
The rainbow-colored scenery
will resonate with my heart
I'm sure any wish I have will come true
Because you're by my side
You make every day feel like a dream
At that warm and kind place
Keep showing me your smiling face forever
Next Time
Episode 12
Birth
Next Time